孤儿怨
坚持住  我明白
Hang on. I know.
你真是好样的
You're doing so good.
真是好样的  你还好吗
You're doing so good. You all right?
-还好  -好的
- Yeah. - Okay.
马修斯医生请到护士站
Dr. Matthews to the nurses' station.
打扰一下
Excuse me.
我妻子要生了  我们已经预约了维勒医生
My wife's in labor. We called ahead for Dr. Wheeler.
请填一下这张表
I just need you to fill this out, please.
-谢谢  -先坐下吧  宝贝
- Thank you. - Have a seat, hon.
-我马上过来  -好的
- I'll be right up. - Yeah.
-行吗  -好的
- Okay? - Okay.
-第一胎吗  -不  不  这是我们第三个了
- Is this your first? - no, no, it's our third.
先生  能在这儿签个字吗
Sir, can you sign here?
我们打算叫她杰西卡
We're gonna name her Jessica.
情况看来不错
Vitals look good.
约翰在哪儿
Where's John?
-我的丈夫在哪儿  -放松点
- Where's my husband? - Just relax now.
会没事的
Everything's gonna be okay.
怎么回事  你们在干什么
What's happening? What are you doing?
我深感抱歉
I'm so sorry for your loss.
-什么  -您的孩子夭折了
- What? - Your baby's dead.
不  它没死  它还活着
No, it's not dead. It's alive.
你说什么  它还在动啊
What are you talking about? It's moving.
这的确很糟糕  我们很抱歉
It's a terrible loss. We're so sorry.
-放松点  -不要
- Just relax. - No!
什么  不  不  让我睡过去  我要睡过去
What? No, no, no. Put me to sleep. I wanna be asleep.
-已经来不及了  -不要
- It's too late for that. - No!
没事的  宝贝  很好
It's okay, honey, you're doing great.
你在干什么  你在干什么
What are you doing? What are you doing?
你可能会有拉扯的感觉
You might feel some tugging.
天哪  这不是真的
Oh, my God. This isn't happening.
恭喜  科尔曼女士  是个女孩儿
Congratulations, Mrs. Coleman. It's a girl.
对  凯特  那些梦可能是你情绪的表现
Yes, Kate, your dreams can be a manifestation of your emotions.
那是你机体对于过去发生的事
It's your body and mind's way of dealing...
造成的压力和痛苦的处理方式
...with the stress and grief of what happened.
要是这和死产没有关系呢
What if this has nothing to do with the stillbirth?
那你认为这和什么有关
What do you think it's about?
这周末我们打算去看孩子
We're seeing kids for the first time this weekend.
或许那些噩梦...
And maybe the nightmares...
或许我还没准备好要收养孩子
Maybe I'm just not ready to adopt yet.
那晚我开车回家路过一家烟酒铺
I drove by the wine shop on the way home the other night.
你停下来了吗
Did you stop?
没  本来想停的  这念头一闪而过
No. Wanted to. The thought went through my brain, you know?
不是想给我自己买  不是...
It wasn't for myself. It wasn't...
我只是想有瓶酒备着总是好的
I just thought it would be nice to have a bottle handy,
以防有客人突然造访
In case we had guests.
但你没进去
But you didn't go in.
在我看来  关键...
The key, to me...
不在于你有喝酒的欲望...
...is not that you had the urge...
而在于你能够克制它
...but that you resisted it.
要是没准备好你也不会通过家庭调研的
You wouldn't have made it through the home study if you weren't ready.
但终究...
But, ultimately...
...决定权还在于你
...you have to decide.
汉姆登聋哑学校
Hamden School For the Deaf
宝贝儿
Honey, hello.
让我看看  是你画的吗
Let me see. Did you paint this?
老师也帮忙了
这蝴蝶真漂亮  太棒了
It's a beautiful butterfly. It's fantastic.
真的很棒  好
Really wonderful. Good.
咱们走吧  冻死我了
Let's go. I'm cold.
你没事吧
Are you okay?
麦可思
Max!
别扔了
Stop throwing!
我在工作呢
I'm working.
对不起
不  宝贝  我才应该道歉
No, honey, I'm sorry.
休息一会儿  行吗
Just take a break for a little while, okay?
因为妈妈要弹琴  好吗
Because Mommy's trying to play. Okay?
爸爸回来了
Daddy's here.
我的了
Mine.
不好意思  训练拖延了一会儿
Sorry, practice went a little late.
没关系
It's all right. whoa.
-好小子  球给我  -真阴险
- Okay, tough guy. Give me that. - Wicked.
不  不
No, no.
投啊  投啊  快  快  快
Shoot it, shoot it. Go, go, go, go.
好  来击个掌
Yes! Give me five.
今天过得怎么样  丹尼尔
Hey, how did it go? Daniel.
还行
Fine.
就玩5分钟  最后一关了
Five minutes. I'm at the last level.
不准玩游戏了  去刷牙
No more video games. Brush your teeth.
这不公平  存不了档  求你了  老爸  行吗
That's no fair. It won't save. Come on, Dad, please?
今晚讲个别的故事吧
那好吧
为了见我刚出生的小妹妹
我等了整整一晚上
但是...
爸爸妈妈回来的时候
妈妈告诉我
我的小妹妹去了天堂
小妹妹去了天堂我很高兴
但我要是先见见她就好了
杰西卡宝宝是天使吗
对  是个漂亮的天使
我还会再有个妹妹吗
我也不知道
圣玛丽亚娜女子孤儿院
St. Mariana Home For Girls
对不起
Sorry.
对不起  对不起  对不起
Sorry, sorry, sorry.
天哪
God.
你真香啊
You smell good.
好吧
Okay.
那好吧
All right.
我不能再这样了
I have to stop being like this.
我明白
I get it.
我很兴奋  很快乐
I'm very excited, I'm happy.
但也很紧张
I get nervous.
我真的好怕
I'm really scared.
上次我感到这一切恰恰是失去孩子之前
Last time I felt all of this was right before I lost the baby.
我不想让你觉得这么做是为了我
I don't want you to feel like we have to go through with this for my sake.
不只是...不只是为你
It's not just... it's not for you.
我想把我们对杰西卡的爱...
I wanna take the love we felt for Jessica...
我想把它给予真正需要它的人
...and I wanna give it to somebody who really needs it.
你想清楚了吗  宝贝
Are you sure, hon?
想清楚了
Yes.
圣玛丽亚娜女子孤儿院
St. Mariana Home For Girls
-想堆雪人吗  -想
- Wanna make a snowman? - Sure.
外面真冷
It's really cold out here.
别闹了
Hey, stop it.
真高兴你们能来
So glad you could make it.
-是啊  -对  真不容易  是吧
- So are we. - Yeah, finally, right?
-见到你真高兴  -谢谢你们能来
- So good to see you. - Thank you for coming.
-真热闹啊  -到处看看吧
- This is really something. - So go take a look around.
-可别惹麻烦  -当然  当然
- Stay out of trouble. - Yeah, yeah.
瞧瞧那个雪堆成的孤儿
Look at the snow orphan.
雪堆成的孤儿?
Snow orphan?
雪孤?
Uh, snorphan?
不  给玛丽修女看
Hey. No, show it to sister Mary.
-慢点  慢点  -你抓不到我
- Slow down, slow down. - You can't catch me.
抓得到
Yes, I can.
这些都是你画的?
Are all these paintings yours?
-对  你喜欢吗  -画得真棒
- Yes. Do you like them? - They're remarkable.
谢谢
Thank you.
我叫艾斯特  你呢
My name is Esther. What's yours?
约翰  见到你很高兴
John. Nice to meet you.
-我能坐下吗  -当然
- Can I take a seat? - Of course.
我怎么也看不烦这些孩子跑啊跳啊的
I never get tired of watching these kids enjoy the party.
真是  真遗憾没能早点来
It really is. I'm so sorry we didn't do this sooner.
别这样  这毕竟是一大步
Don't be. It's a big leap.
收养一个年纪大点的孩子没法轻易决定
Adopting an older child is not an easy decision to make.
约翰去卫生间了
John's in the bathroom.
他能找到我们吗  还是去找找他?
Think he'll find us? Do you wanna go look for him?
你这幅画的灵感是什么
Where did you get the idea for this one?
我的画总是有故事的
My paintings always tell stories.
这幅画是讲一个找不到幼崽的伤心的母狮子
This one's about a sad mother lion who can't find her cubs.
-可她在微笑  -她梦见自己的宝宝了
- She's smiling. - She's dreaming about her babies.
只有这个能让她高兴起来
It's the only thing that makes her happy.
-希望她能找到孩子  -会的  看
- I hope she finds them. - She will. Look.
他们在森林里迷路了  又惊又怕...
They were lost in the jungle, and they were so scared...
因为他们找不到爸爸妈妈了
...because they didn't have a mother or father.
正当他们以为要永远孤单下去的时候...
Just when they thought they'd be alone forever...
他们发现妈妈在这棵树下熟睡着
...they found their mother asleep under this tree.
现在等她醒了  她的梦想也就成真了
Now when she wakes up, her dream will have come true.
-她又有家人了  -真棒  这故事是你想出来的?
- She'll have her family again. - Amazing. You came up with that story?
-我听到他的声音了  -对
- I think I hear his voice down here. - Yes.
介绍一下  这是我妻子  凯特
I want to introduce you. This is my wife, Kate.
凯特  这是艾斯特
Kate, this is Esther.
你好  见到你真高兴
How are you? Nice to meet you.
这些都是她画的
She painted all these.
-真的?  -对
- Really? - Yeah.
画得太漂亮了  真的很棒
These are fantastic. These are really wonderful.
-谢谢  -你是从哪儿学的
- Thank you. - Where did you learn how to do this?
我想只是我练习的时间很多罢了
I've just had lots of time to practice, I guess.
这里真的很无聊
It's really boring here.
这儿很无聊?
It's boring here?
你要是无聊  干吗不下去参加派对呢
If you're so bored, why aren't you down at the party?
我一直觉得那没什么意义
I've never really seen the point of it.
以前也没人跟我说过话
Nobody's ever talked to me before.
我想我比较特别吧
I guess I'm different.
特别一点没什么不好的
There's nothing wrong with being different.
你们俩共同点还挺多
Well, you two have a lot in common.
我认为人们总应该...
I think people should always...
承受自己身上发生的不幸...
...try to take the bad things that happen to them...
...并化不幸为幸事
...and turn them into something good.
-你觉得呢  -是啊
- Don't you? - Yeah.
当然
Absolutely.
她是从俄罗斯来的  但英文好得惊人
She's originally from Russia, but it's amazing how strong her English is.
她来美国才几年而已
Given she's only been in the country a few years.
你们经常收留外国孩子?
How often do you get children from other countries?
很少  有时外国孩子很难适应
It's rare. But when we do, it's sometimes difficult to place them.
把她带来美国的那家人因房子失火丧生了
The family that brought her to America died in a house fire.
失火?
In a fire?
我的天啊
My God.
艾斯特险些丧命
Esther barely got out.
她经历了不少  但这是个出色的小姑娘
She's been through a lot, but this is an extraordinary little girl.
她很聪明  比同龄人成熟很多
She's very bright. She's very mature for her age.
而且很有教养  说实话  有点像小公主
And she's very well-mannered. She's a bit of a princess, actually.
她的脖子和手腕上一直系着缎带
She wears those ribbons on her wrists and her neck all the time.
我也是
Mine too.
我们想给她解下来时  她还死活不愿意
We had trouble with her when we tried to take them off.
她和其他孩子相处得怎么样
How does she get along with other kids?
她不得不交流的时候  表现很好
Oh, when she has to interact, she's great.
亲爱的?
Babe?
-她好像真愿跟我们说心里话  -对
- She really did seem to open up with us. - Yeah.
我认为她不只愿跟你们说心里话
I thought she more than opened up with you.
你们看来已经像一家人了
You seem to have made quite a connection.
我可以把手续备齐  3周后你们再过来
I could get the paperwork together and see you back here in three weeks.
好的
All right.
太好了
Okey-dokey.
有事再电话联系
Call me if you need anything.
再见  好  谢谢
Bye. Okay, thank you.
那是T和H
Oh, that's t-h.
T和H  对
T-h. Yeah.
"麦可思"是这样表示吗
And "Max" is like this?
对
Yeah.
不错
Good.
-这是你们的家吗  -现在也是你家了
- Is this your house? - Now it's your house too.
宝贝  看看谁来了
Hi, sweetie. Look who's here.
你好  麦可思  我叫艾斯特
Hello, Max. My name is Esther.
她一路上一直在练习
She's been practicing the whole way.
-她能听见吗  -就一点儿
- Can she hear?  - A little.
她生下来几乎全聋
She was born almost completely deaf.
那点听力对她读唇语刚刚足够
That just allows her to hear enough to read lips.
没关系  行李我拎好了
That's all right, I got it.
艾斯特  来认识一下芭芭拉奶奶
Esther, I'd like to introduce you to grandma Barbara.
见到您很高兴
It's a pleasure to meet you.
真是个小甜心  见到你我也很高兴
That's precious. It's a pleasure to meet you too.
丹尼
Danny.
这是艾斯特
This is Esther.
你好  丹尼尔
Hello, Daniel.
她为什么穿成那样
Why does she dress like that?
-行了  住嘴  -我只是问问而已
- Come on. Stop it. - I'm just asking a question.
-你们有钢琴?  -对
- You have a piano? - Yeah.
-想学吗  -我很乐意
- Would you like to learn how to play? - I would love to.
喜欢吗
Do you like it?
-太完美了  -好
- It's perfect. - Good.
谢谢
Thank you.
怎么说"谢谢"?
How do you say "thank you"?
谢谢
Thank you.
不客气
瞧瞧那个
Wow, look at that.
什么  什么  什么
What? What? What?
爸  看啊
Dad, look.
-爸  -你从哪儿找到的
- Dad. - Where did you get that?
-爸  看  我要打败特莱弗了  -真棒
- Dad, look, I'm killing Trevor. - Great.
谢谢
Thank you.
来啊  爸爸  我的独奏快完了  快看哪
Come on, Dad. My solo's gonna end. Hurry, look.
太酷了
Wow, cool.
-特莱弗  你逊毙了  -闭嘴
- Trevor, you suck. - Shut up.
真不错
That's fabulous.
走吧  伙计们  真没意思
Come on, guys. This is lame.
我差点就要赢你了
I was just about to beat you.
你喜欢就好  宝贝
I'm glad you like it, honey.
快点  伙计们
Come on, guys.
快点  我快冻死了
Hurry up, I'm freezing my ass off.
-伙计们  都在这儿  -天哪  我的手都冻僵了
- Dude, it's all in here. - Oh, God. My hands are freezing.
她真性感
Oh, man, she's hot.
-往那边挪点  伙计  -34页会让你终生难忘的
- Move over, man. - Page 34 will change your life.
这个看起来像你妈
This looks like your Mom.
不
No.
艾斯特和玛克辛看来相处得不错
Esther and Maxine seem to be getting along well.
对
Yeah.
她怎么样  凯特
How's she doing, Kate?
艾斯特适应得挺快
Esther's fitting right in.
我是说玛克辛
I meant Maxine.
她在池塘边玩好像什么也没发生过一样
She's playing by the pond like nothing ever happened.
她不记得了  对吧
She doesn't remember, does she?
对  她很好
No. She's fine.
那么  你怎么打算的
So, what are your plans?
大概先帮艾斯特好好适应一下...
You know, probably get Esther settled...
然后再去教课
...then go back to teaching.
学校不是不让你回去了吗
Thought they weren't gonna take you back.
不  我不是说回耶鲁
No, I'm not talking about Yale.
我就...或许在家里教教课吧
I'll just... I'll probably give lessons from home.
真可惜  那工作多好啊
That's too bad. That was a very good job.
又不是我不想干的
Well, I didn't quit because I wanted to.
我明白  你必须花时间来"净身"
I know. You had to have your moment of clarity.
那是戒酒协会的术语
That is an a.a. term.
我又没去戒酒协会  我只是不喝了
And I didn't go to a.a. I just stopped drinking.
还不是一样  有时我们都需要清醒清醒
Same difference. We all need a wake-up call sometimes.
来
Come here.
什么事
Yeah?
我们害怕闪电
We're scared of the lightning.
进来吧
Oh, come in.
-我想挨着爸爸睡  -等会儿
- I wanna sleep next to Daddy. - Hang on.
好了
Okay.
我等会儿打电话回来  确保一切顺利
I'm gonna call later, make sure everything's okay.
好的  你的设计会大受欢迎的
Okay. They're gonna love your design.
-等会儿接电话好吗  -好的
- You gonna pick up the phone? - Yeah.
好的
All right.
艾斯特?
Esther?
快点
Come on.
艾斯特  快点  咱们该走了
Esther, come on, we gotta go!
开什么玩笑
You gotta be kidding me.
-你们去车里等着好吗  -走吧
- Will you please go wait in the car? - Come on.
宝贝  穿这裙子上学可不合适
Sweetheart, this isn't really a school dress.
但我喜欢  你不觉得很漂亮吗
But I like it. Don't you think it's pretty?
对  的确很漂亮...
Yes, it's so beautiful...
但我想你穿这个会不舒服的
...but I just don't think you're gonna be comfortable in it.
穿我给你买的那条牛仔裤怎么样
What about those jeans that I bought you?
你担心其他同学会笑话我  对吧
You're afraid the other children will laugh at me, aren't you?
你不是说过特别一点没什么不好吗
I thought you said there wasn't anything wrong with being different.
对  你说得对  说得很对
Yes, you're right. You're absolutely right.
好吧  开心点
Okay. Have fun.
请坐好  坐好
Take a seat, please. Take a seat.
请别再让我说一遍
Don't make me ask again, please.
这是我们的新同学  她叫艾斯特·科尔曼
Okay, this is our new student. Her name's Esther Coleman.
我希望今天大家能对她热情一点
And I'd like you all to make her feel very welcome today.
瞧  小宝皮给我发了个短信
Oh, look. Little Bo Peep texted me.
她想要回她的裙子
She wants her outfit back.
好  去坐下吧
Okay, go take a seat.
请大家把书翻到27页...
Okay, if everybody could turn to page 27...
不
No!
不  艾斯特  你在干什么
No! Esther, what are you doing?
离开那儿  不要
Get away from there! No!
不准在池塘附近玩  你知道的
You don't play near the water! You know that!
快点  快出来
Come on, get out!
麦可思
Max.
真棒  正中红心
Sweet. Bull's-eye.
打中你了
Got you.
-你把它打死了?  -只是个颜料球
- Did you kill it? - It's just a paint ball.
我没想到会伤害它
I didn't think it would hurt him.
让它解脱痛苦吧
Put it out of its misery.
它很痛苦  这是你的责任
It's in pain, and it's your responsibility.
这只是个意外
It was just an accident.
如果你现在走了  它就得饿死
If you walk away now, it'll starve to death.
你想那样吗
Is that what you want?
我什么都没做
I'm not doing it.
好了
It's all right.
-它现在已经在天堂了  -你神经病
- It's in heaven now. - What's wrong with you?
-水热吗   -热  谢谢
- Is the water warm enough?  - Yes, thank you.
好的  有事叫我
Okay. Call me if you need anything.
艾斯特?
Esther?
艾斯特
Esther.
把门打开
Open this door.
-你在做什么  -我一般都把门锁上的
- What are you doing? - I always lock the door.
不  在家里我们不用锁门
No, we don't lock doors in this house.
但是万一有人进来看到我怎么办
But what if someone comes in and sees me?
没人会进来
Nobody's gonna come in.
好吧  我就在这儿站着  如果你想这样
Look, I'm gonna stand right here, if that's what you want.
我可以给你唱歌
I could sing for you.
我以前常常给我姐妹们唱歌  那样他们就知道我没事了
I used to sing for the sisters so they would know I was all right.
好吧
Okay.
好吧  但是你要知道  只有今晚这样
All right. But you know what? This is just for tonight.
你父母一定去了很多孤儿院才找到她
Your parents must have gone to a lot of retard camps to find her.
看着点
Watch it.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
这是圣经吗
Is this a Bible?
耶稣迷今天带圣经来学校了
Jesus freak brought a Bible to school today.
想拿回去吗
Hey, wanna come over?
-好样的  -你妹妹是一个十足的笨蛋
- Good one. - Your sister's a total spaz.
她不是我妹妹
She's not my sister.
真不敢相信你会那么做
I can't believe you did that.
小巴狗  这是你的项圈吗  小巴狗?
Oh, little doggy. Is this your collar, little doggy?
不  A  A  B
Not a. a, b.
你弹得真的很不错
You did really good.
不  不好  我错了11处
No, I didn't. I made like 11 mistakes.
下次我会弹得更好的
I'll do better next time.
老师告诉我今天学校发生的事了
Your teacher told me what happened today.
你想和我谈谈吗
Don't you want to talk about it?
没什么可谈的
There's nothing to talk about.
你知道我是为你来的  好吧  你知道的是吗
You know I'm here for you, right? You know that, right?
我有件东西想给你看
I got something I wanna show you.
我有这么个本子  用来写日记
I have one just like this that I use as a diary.
我想也许我们可以一起用这个...
And I thought that maybe you and I could use this one...
...做个剪贴簿
...for a scrapbook.
这是爸爸和妈妈结婚的日子
That's Mommy and Daddy on their wedding day.
这是丹尼尔  圣诞节的早晨
That's Daniel, Christmas morning.
这个是麦可思
Here's Max.
这个是你
And there's you.
杰西卡是谁
Who's Jessica?
麦可思提起过她
Max talks about her.
"我从没抱过你  但我能感觉到你"
"I never held you, but I feel you."
"你从未说过话  但我能聆听到你"
"You never spoke, but I hear you."
"我从没未了解你  但是我爱你"
"I never knew you, but I love you."
她怎么了
What happened to her?
她死了  还在我肚子里的时候
She died while she was still in my tummy.
我们把她的骨灰埋葬在这儿
But we scattered her ashes here.
随着这棵植物的生长...
And as long as this plant grows...
...她也会有部分存活在其中
...then part of her will be alive inside it.
她应该是幸运的
She would have been lucky.
你是一个伟大的妈妈
You're a great Mommy.
谢谢  甜心
Thank you, sweetheart.
谢谢  这很有意义
Thank you. It means a lot.
-你好吗   -很好
- How are you? - I'm good.
太有趣了  艾斯特今天开始说话了
It's very interesting. Esther started to open up today.
真是太有趣了
That's very interesting.
我开始觉得这是一次真正的交流
I'm starting to feel like there's a real connection.
我也是
Me too.
不  亲爱的  这儿不行
No, honey, not here.
他们都睡着了
They're sleeping.
宝贝  来吧  你会喜欢的  相信我
Baby, come here, you'll like it, believe me.
-好吧  我们言归正传  -不  不  不
- Okay, let's get down to business. - No, no, no.
来吧  就几分钟
Okay, just for a second, then.
好吧
Yeah.
-不  不  不  -来吧
- No, no, no. - Come on.
我要  等等  等等
I have to. Wait, wait, wait.
很好
Yeah.
对不起
Oh, sorry.
上帝
Oh, Jesus.
上帝  亲爱的  真该死
Jesus, honey. Damn it.
艾斯特?
Esther?
我们得谈谈昨天晚上的事
We have to talk about last night.
-需要吗  -是的  必须
- Do we? - Yes, we do.
听着  有些大人做的事情...
See, there are certain things that grown-ups do...
...小孩子不应该偷看
...that children aren't supposed to see.
那就是其中一件
And that was one of them.
艾斯特  听我说
Esther, listen to me.
当大人们彼此非常非常相爱的时候...
When grown-ups love each other very, very much...
他们就想要表示这种爱  把它表达出来
...they wanna show each other that love. Express it.
我知道  他们就会操
I know. They fuck.
她一定在哪儿学到的  也许是学校
She could've picked it up anywhere. Probably at school.
这并不是她偶然听到的  我觉得她懂得其中的含义
This wasn't something she overheard. I mean, she knew what it meant.
而且  亲爱的  她说话的方式...
And, babe, the way she said it is...
我甚至觉得她都没有因为此事而感到烦恼
I don't even think she expected to get in trouble over it.
好吧  今天晚上我们和她谈谈
Well, we'll talk to her about it tonight.
好的
Fine.
那么  你有什么想法
Well, what did you have in mind?
没有  我想我们应该带她去布朗宁医生那里
No, I thought we could take her to Dr. Browning.
我觉得还没有带她去看心理医生的必要
I don't think we need to take her to the shrink quite yet.
可是  我们还不很了解她
Well, you know, we just don't know that much about her.
她所在的家庭就是吃饭的时候说着"把他妈的土豆拿开"
The family she stayed with "pass the fucking potatoes" at dinnertime,
你知道吗
You know?
如果她当着我的面会这么说  我们不在的时候她又会说什么
If she's saying it to my face, what is she saying when we're not there?
我可不想让她的这种思想影响到麦可思
I don't want her exerting that kind of influence over Max.
不管怎样  我可不希望这一个词会惹出大麻烦
Anyway, I just don't want to make a big deal out of one little dirty word.
好  你他妈就跟她耗时间吧
Fine. Fucking spend some time with her, then.
没错  泼妇
All right, bitch.
我们去打雪仗吧
Let's have a snow fight!
快来  别扔雪球
come on, no throwing snowballs.
你好  老邻居
Hey, neighbor.
好久没见到你了
Haven't seen you around lately.
我最近特别忙
I've been pretty busy.
业主协会没有了我还能坚持吗
Has the homeowners' association been soldiering on without me?
这不一样
It's not the same.
其实  我想让你帮个忙
Um, actually, I had a favor to ask.
有把椅子我想把它搬到楼上...
I have a chair that I need moved upstairs...
...我希望你哪天有空能顺便来帮我
...and I was hoping you could come by and help me with that sometime.
好的
Yeah.
-好的  当然   -谢谢
- Yeah, sure. - Good.
也许我和凯特可以帮得上忙  告诉我们就行
Maybe Kate and I could help you out. Just let us know.
我会告诉你的
I'll call you.
走吧  宝贝
Let's go, honey.
好的  我看着你呢
Okay, I'm watching you.
布伦达的爸爸说是你把她退下去的
Brenda's father says that you pushed her.
不是的
That's not true.
我们只是在玩
We were just playing.
我发誓
I swear.
-好  -你看到发生什么了吗
- Okay. - And did you see what happened?
她滑倒了
什么  妈妈  她在说什么
What? Mom, what's she saying?
她想让你把面包和黄油递过去
She wants you to pass the bread and butter.
没问你
Wasn't asking you.
你能正常点吃吗
Can you eat normal?
我吃得很正常
I am eating normal.
是的  可能在特兰西瓦尼亚  或者你来的那个国家算正常的
Yeah, maybe in Transylvania, or whatever country you're from.
顺便说一下  我是从俄罗斯来的
Incidentally, I'm from Russia.
特兰西瓦尼亚并不是一个国家  它是罗马尼亚的一部分
Transylvania isn't even a country. It's a part of Romania.
你个怪胎
You are such a freak.
丹尼
Hey, Danny.
我可不想再听到你这么说话
I don't want any more talk like that.
但为什么她能那么做呢
But why does she have to act like that?
所有朋友都笑话我  就是因为她
All my friends make fun of me because of her.
也许你需要不同的朋友
Maybe you need different friends.
也许你需要把她送回孤儿院
Maybe you should send her back to the retard camp.
-丹尼尔   -丹尼尔
- Daniel. - Daniel.
和你妹妹道歉
Apologize to your sister.
她他妈才不是我妹妹
She's not my fucking sister.
我来解决
I got it.
好吧
Okay.
我来
That's me.
你道歉了就能拿回钥匙
You get the key back when you say you're sorry.
今天晚上想让我做什么好吃的呢
Is there anything special you want me to make tonight?
你爱吃什么
You have any favorites?
喂
Hello.
-你还好吗  -我们很好  我们相处很好
- Well, how are you? - Hi, we're great. We're doing good.
-她怎么样   -她就在这儿  等等
- How is she? - She's here, hold on.
是阿比盖尔修女  你想和她问个好吗
Hey, sister Abigail. Do you wanna say hello?
-来吧  艾斯特  只是很快地问个好   -我说了  不要
- Come on. Esther, just quickly say hi. - I said, no.
亲爱的  能帮我装5个苹果吗
You know what, do you mind, darling, can you get five apples for me?
对不起  她突然变得很害羞
Sorry, she got shy all of a sudden.
没关系  我只是想提醒你...
It's all right. I'm just calling to remind you...
我的监督报告需要她的...
...that I'm gonna need her medical...
内科和牙科表格
...and dental charts for my supervision report.
她在说什么
她不喜欢牙医
She's not thrilled about the dentist.
她在谈论你
大家相处怎么样  她对你们开口了吗
How is everyone doing? Is she opening up to you?
我就猜到你会问这个  几个星期之前她给我出了个难题
I guess you can say that. She dropped the f-bomb on me a few weeks ago.
"难题"是什么
我猜她最后一定会逃出她的外壳
I guess she's finally coming out of her shell.
是的
Yeah.
还有其他事要告诉我的吗
Any other glitches I should know of?
目前我们出现一个大问题
We had a big one recently.
学校里有个叫布伦达的女孩
It's a girl named Brenda at school.
她在说布伦达的事儿
她们在操场的一架滑梯上玩  她掉了下来
They were at the playground, there was a slide, well, she fell off.
艾斯特可能推了她
Esther may have pushed her down.
我不想让事情严重化  但是她受伤了
I'm not getting the story straight, but she got hurt.
她还好吗
Is she all right?
还算走运  她伤了踝关节还缝了6针
Luckily. She broke her ankle and had something like six stitches.
听起来不怎么走运
That doesn't sound too lucky.
是啊  幸好没有伤到脖子
Well, she's lucky she didn't break her neck.
你和我说过你不会弹的
You told me you didn't know how to play.
-不  我没说  -说了  你说了
- No, I didn't. - Yes, you did.
是你主动教我的  而我接受了
You offered to teach me and I accepted.
好的  所以你一直都在装
Okay. So then you were just pretending this whole time?
我以为你很喜欢教我
I thought you would enjoy teaching me.
对于一个像你这样热爱音乐的人...
It must be frustrating for someone who loves music as much as you...
子女对音乐毫无兴趣是一件多么沮丧的事
...to have a son who isn't interested and a daughter who can't even hear.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
我进去的时候她完美地弹着柴可夫斯基的曲子
I walk in on her playing Tchaikovsky without a mistake.
她一直都在骗我
I mean, she's been lying to me this whole time.
她只是想让你陪她  这不算撒谎
She just wants to spend time with you. It's hardly a lie.
你根本不懂
You wouldn't know.
你不懂  她在你面前总是表现得很好
You wouldn't. She's on her best behavior with you.
在我面前却截然相反
She's completely different with me.
那么  你想说什么
So, what are you saying?
我也不知道  她在学校大发脾气
I don't know. She threw a fit at school.
她把布伦达推到地上
She pushed Brenda at the playground.
-现在你的意思是那是她的错?  -我也不知道
- Now you're saying that was her fault? - I don't know.
亲爱的  我也不知道
Honey, I don't know.
我并不在场  你看着她们的
I wasn't there. You were watching them.
亲爱的  那是场意外
Oh, come on. It was an accident.
好  我们什么都不要责怪她  好吗
Okay, let's not blame her for anything, fine.
我以后所有事情都相信她
I'll take her word for everything.
我也应该相信她说的关于你和乔伊斯的话吗
Should I just believe what she said about you and Joyce too?
她说什么了
What did she say?
-她说你爱上她了  -什么
- She says that you were hitting on her. - What?
拜托  她一定误会了  那是...
Oh, come on. She must've misunderstood. It was, like...
她请你过去的吗
Did she invite you over?
她叫我帮她搬椅子
She asked me to help her move a chair.
-她叫你了  -是的  但我拒绝了
- She did? - Yeah. I blew her off
天哪
Oh, God.
你怎么不告诉我
Why didn't you tell me?
-我...  -这真是可笑
- I... - We could've laughed about it.
-不  我知道...  -你想掩饰
- No, I knew how... - You were hiding it.
亲爱的  我知道你会生气
Honey, I knew how you'd react.
凯特  凯特
Kate. Kate.
你别像其他女人一样满腹猜疑好吗
You can't get jealous of every woman that I talk to, right?
-已经将近10年了   -那又怎样
- It's been like 10 years. - What does that mean?
你这么说代表这的确意味着什么
You say that like it actually means something.
你才刚告诉我2年
It's only been two years since you told me.
你知道我有多对不起你  我只想赢得一点信任
You know how sorry I am. I just feel like I've earned a little trust here.
-我已经给你第二次机会了   -那不公平  那不公平
- I gave you a second chance. - That's not fair. That's not fair.
我直说吧  我们谈论的是我的错  不是你的
Let me get this straight. We can talk about my mistakes, not yours?
真让我恶心  你就是个想上其他人的白痴
I was sick! You were an asshole who wanted to fuck somebody else!
你置我们孩子的安危于不顾
You put our child's life in danger.
我应该离开几个月  就没人再责备我了
I could've walked away months ago. Nobody would've blamed me.
很干脆  很干脆  你从哪儿学来的  你妈那儿吗
Oh, that's sharp. That's sharp. Where did you get that from, your mother?
丹尼  声音关小点  拜托  我要工作
Danny. Turn that crap down, please, I gotta work.
-好吧  -谢谢
- Fine. - Thank you.
我去开
I'll get it.
-你好  艾斯特  -你来这儿干吗
- Hello, Esther. - What are you doing here?
我可以进去吗
May I come in?
恐怕我犯了一个错误
I'm afraid I may have made a mistake.
艾斯特可能有点问题
There could be something wrong with Esther.
什么
What?
什么  你说过她一点问题都没有的
What? You told us that you'd never had any trouble with her.
是的  但麻烦是会找上她的
I didn't. But trouble does have a way of finding her.
什么样的麻烦
What kind of trouble?
两个女孩打架  她是其中一个
Two girls get into a fight, there she is.
有人偷东西被抓  她又在其中
Someone gets caught stealing, there she is again.
-那么  意思就是...  -让她说完
- So? Does that mean...? - Just let her finish.
你告诉我摔到地上那个女孩的事之后
After you told me about the girl in the playground,
我给她以前的学校打了电话
I called her old school.
她在那儿的时候  有一个男孩...
While she was there, there was a boy...
手里拿着剪子...
...who fell with scissors in his hand...
并且突然刺穿了自己的下巴
...and accidentally stabbed himself through the jaw.
当时艾斯特也在场
And Esther was there again.
我不明白  他突然刺伤了他自己
I don't understand. He accidentally stabbed himself.
但是最大的麻烦是苏利文房屋的火灾
But the most troubling thing is the Sullivan house fire.
我做了进一步调查  那是纵火
I checked into it further. It was arson.
他们一直都没查出谁是凶手
They have never found the person who did it.
你有什么建议
What are you suggesting here?
她与这些事情有什么联系
That she had anything to do with any of this?
这太可笑了
It's ridiculous.
一个孩子能够做出这种违法的事...
That a child could commit such crimes...
我相信这只是表面现象
...it flies in the face of everything I believe.
是的
Well, yeah.
来了一个可恶的女人  她要把我带走
There's a mean lady here. She's come to take me away.
你能帮我吗
Will you help me?
我们有一些行为问题  但是...
We've had some behavioral problems, but...
是的  不会是那样的  是吧
Yeah, nothing like that. I mean, right?
是的  真的  考虑一下吧
Yes, we have. Really, hon, think about it.
我会试着联系那家她长大的俄罗斯孤儿院
I've tried to reach the Russian orphanage where she was raised.
我们需要知道该怎么办
I think we need to know what we're dealing with.
好的  我会告诉你们该怎么办
Well, I'll tell you what we're dealing with.
-不...  -别说话  听着
- No, you know what? - Stop it. Listen.
我们在对待一个9岁的孤儿  明白吗
We're dealing with a 9-year-old girl who's an orphan, okay?
-我们要带她去看布朗宁医生  -我们带她去看布朗宁医生
- We're taking her to Dr. Browning. - We can take her to Dr. Browning.
找到树屋的钥匙
你想玩吗
Do you want to play?
一旦我查出来就会立刻给你电话
I'll call you as soon as I find anything else out.
-好的  保重  -好的  非常感谢
- Right. Take care.  - Okay. Thank you very much.
待会儿再说
Maybe later.
会没事的
It's going to be fine.
我们要把她吓得再也不敢来
We'll scare her so bad she'll never come back here.
她来了
Here she comes.
挥舞你的手臂让她停下
Wave your arms and make her stop.
麦可思  快去
Max, go.
你没事吧  麦可思
You all right? Max?
麦可思?
Max?
你还好吗
You okay?
别哭了
Stop crying.
抓住一只脚  帮我把她拖到路边
Grab a foot and help me get her off the road.
快点
Now.
帮我把她藏起来
Help me hide her.
你骗我
没关系
That doesn't matter.
他们会送你去监狱的  快帮我把她藏起来
They'll send you to jail just for helping me hide her.
我必须杀了她  因为她会去告我的
I had to kill her because she was going to tell on me.
你不会去告我吧  是吗
You're not going to tell on me. Are you?
别害怕
Don't worry.
你是我妹妹
You're my little sister.
我不会让你有事的
I won't let anything happen to you.
我爱你
I love you.
告诉我  你看到了什么
Tell me what you saw.
-你要干什么  -你看到了什么
- What are you doing? - What did you see?
我看到你和麦可思在树屋里
I saw you and Max in the tree house.
还有呢
What else?
-你什么意思  -你还看到了什么
- What do you mean? - What else did you see?
我什么都没看到  我发誓
I didn't see anything. I swear.
-你有告诉别人吗  -没有
- Did you tell anyone? - No.
我谁都没告诉
I didn't tell anyone.
求你了...
Please...
如果我发现你说谎
If I find out that you're lying, I'll cut your hairless little prick off..
我会让你连怎么死的都不知道
...before you even figure out what it's for.
-明白了吗  -明白了
- Do you understand me? - Yes.
你尿床了
You pissed yourself.
很高兴和你谈话  爱丽丝  希望我们能成为朋友
It was nice talking to you, Alice. I hope we can be friends.
我也是
I'd like that.
-我们很快就出来  亲爱的  -你一会儿再进来
- We'll be right out, honey. - You can come on in.
我的直觉告诉我
My initial instinct is that...
艾斯特的过去没有什么太大的问题
...there's not a deeply-rooted problem in Esther's past.
-她没有问题  -是的
- So there's nothing wrong with her? - No.
这不全是好消息  我认为艾斯特和身边人的关系...
It's not all good news. I think what needs to be examined...
还是需要考察的
...is Esther's relationship with those around her.